A lot of the work I do is behind the
scenes, but it makes it worth it because
I love football and I love contributing
to what we're building here.
>> [music]
>> I'm Peyton Roth, I'm a scouting
coordinator for the Tampa Bay
Buccaneers.
>> [music]
[music]
>> Before we head off to the combine in
Indianapolis, there's a handful of items
I have to check off my list here in
Tampa. Mostly combine books,
credentials, scheduling, making sure
everyone's good to go with travel.
After that, I'll work with Spencer Dill,
our director of IT, to kind of build out
the book. So, that kind of includes, you
know, just general combine information,
our informal [music] interviews, and
then just our formal interviews as well.
So, that will all go into the book. No
two books are alike, that's very
important. Once those books are
completed, I'll [music] kind of get eyes
on them, go through them, make sure
everyone's books are good to go.
Once I do that, I'll ship them out to
Indy and they will be here when when I
arrive.
We have about 450 [music]
guys that we make cut-ups for throughout
the year, and these are mostly done for
Jason, [music] Todd Bowles, any coach
that wants to watch.
These film cut-ups that we make
throughout the season, they look a
little [music] bit different for every
position. We take evaluative plays, so
good, [music] bad, big plays, and we
just kind of compile it together to make
a cut-up um that's easier to kind of
narrow in on the player that we're
talking about.
So, we have a certain number [music] of
color tags, so my settings are
red [music] for run,
blue for pass. I have three for uh PBU.
>> [music]
>> I have four for pressure. I have five
for like interception. Once I'm done
watching four games, I kind of [music]
sort them. I do
um plays versus the run, plays versus
the pass, um any big plays I want to add
at the end. Once we get these All-Star
[music] games in and the combine stuff
and pro days, I'll put that on the back
end and
pretty much wraps up the cut-up.
So, I land in Indy, the scouting staff
uh we get here on Monday, and informal
interviews [music] and formal interviews
start on Monday. One of the scouting
assistants will usually go grab the
books from FedEx that we shipped out.
Shannon Cogan always helps me out, one
of our pro scouts. We'll walk over, pick
up the credentials in bulk, cross-check
that [music] with our rooming list, make
sure everyone's credentials are good to
go.
Take them back to my room, I'll post up
with the books and the credentials. I'll
send everyone a group chat like, "Hey,
swing by [music] my room, grab your
stuff, and let's get going."
The formal interview process is kind of
crazy. And it's 20-minute [music]
time slots starting at 7:00 p.m. and
going all the way to 11:00 p.m. and
we're usually packed during that. We
have about 12 interviews. [music] So,
what I'll do is, let's say the Saints
are interviewing the guy that we're
going to we're going to interview next,
I will walk down to the Saints interview
[music] suite about 5 minutes before,
and then once the interview is over,
I'll grab him, walk him back to our
suite,
>> [music]
>> and then the interview will restart. All
32 teams have a suite in one hallway.
It's very hectic, [music] there are a
lot of people. So, I think it's
important that I'm there to grab the
guy. [music]
We have a 2-minute passing period to get
to our suite, and I think that [music]
if I wasn't there, you know, they may
get sidetracked, you know, people might
pull them aside, try to [music] talk to
them, they might see their friends. So,
it's important that I grab them, we kind
of make small talk along the way, get to
know the [music] guy,
drop them off at our suite, and then I
do it again. As I'm walking with them
during this like 2-minute [music]
passing period, I really try to just
like kind of loosen the guys up. Some of
them are pretty nervous, some of them
it's their
>> [music]
>> 20th interview of the week and they're
fine. But, obviously we want to talk to
these guys, we want to get to know these
guys, will they fit in our building,
will they raise the temperature of our
room. Obviously, our scouts do a great
job out on the road all year, but it's
important for Jason, Mike, and [music]
Rob to talk to these guys in person, and
then obviously seeing them work out in
person is huge as well.
Once the workouts start, [music] I'm
going to be over at 40s with Andy Spire
and Tony Hardy timing all of those. It's
an awesome process, it's really fun. Uh
we have some friendly competition going
over there, so it's a really good time.
We'll time the 40s for all the
positions, come back over to the suite,
eat some food, [music] watch the
on-field drills, then we'll do it all
over again for for every position. After
the draft [music] ends in April, we
start on the next year. We're building
out our draft board year-round. [music]
We start on these guys early. So, to be
at the combine in Indy, kind of seeing
the picture come together, knowing the
draft is, you know, a [music] month or
two away, it's really cool to see all
the work that we've been doing on these
guys
>> [music]
>> is paying off, and we're targeting the
right guys that we think would would fit
in.